在我开始讲技术内容之前，我想讲一点密码学的历史
Before we start with the technical
material, I want to tell you a little bit
关于密码学的历史，David Kahn写了一本很棒的书
about the history of cryptography. There's
a beautiful book on this topic by David
叫密码破译者,它概括了完整的密码学历史
Kahn called the codebreakers. It covers
the history of cryptography all the way
从古巴比伦时代到现在，我将给大家看
from the Babylonian era, to the
present. Here, I'm just going to give you
一些历史上已经被完全破解的密码方案的例子
a few examples of historical ciphers, all
of which are badly broken. So to talk
谈论到密码，首先要介绍我的朋友Alice和Bob
about ciphers the first thing I'm going to
do is introduce our friends Alice and Bob,
他们将伴随我们所有余下的课程,Alice与Bob试图安全的通信
who are gonna be with us for the rest of
the quarter. So Alice and Bob are trying
但有一个攻击者试图窃听他们的对话
to communicate securely and there is an
attacker who's trying to eavesdrop on
因此为了安全通信，他们将分享一个密钥
their conversation. So to communicate
securely, they're going to share a secret
我将它记为k,他两都知道这个密钥
key, which I'll denote by K. They both know
the secret key. But the attacker does not
但攻击者不知道。现在他们将使用加密方案
know anything about this key K.
So now they're gonna use a cipher, which
其实是一对算法，加密算法记为E
is a pair of algorithms, an
encryption algorithm denoted by E, and a
解密算法记为D，这些算法工作如下：
decryption algorithm, D. These algorithms
work as follows: the encryption algorithm
加密算法E需要信息原文m和密钥k作为输入
E takes the message M as inputs. And it
takes as inputs, the key K. I'm gonna
我在k上面画一个楔形标记是为了强调这个输入是密钥
put a wedge above the key input just
to denote the fact that this input is
然后它输出E加密算法用k密钥算出的密文
really the key input. And then it outputs
a ciphertext. Which is the encryption of
我总是将密钥写在前面
the message M using the key K. I'm always
gonna write the key first. Now, and when I
用=意味这个表达式是定义c，变量c代表什么
write: = what I mean is that the
expression defines what C what the
现在密文通过网络传输给Bob
variable C stands for. Now the ciphertext
is transmitted over the internet to Bob,
事实上它可以是网络传输，也可以是
somehow. Actually it could be transmitted
over the internet. Could be transmitted
使用加密文件系统传输，这都没有多大关系。但是当密文
using an encrypted file system, it doesn't
really matter, but when the ciphertext
发给Bob，他可以把它放到解密算法
reaches Bob, he can plug it into the
decryption algorithm and give the
并给解密算法一个一样的密钥k，我也做一个楔形标记
decryption algorithm the same key K.
Again, I'm gonna put a wedge here as well. To
来强调输入为密钥k，解密算法输出原始明文
denote the key inputs and the decryption
algorithm outputs the original plaintext
现在我想说明这里是对称加密，即加密与解密
message. Now the reason we say that these
are symmetric ciphers is that both the
事实上用的是同一个密钥k。正如我们后面将看到的
encrypter and decrypter actually use the
same key K. As we'll see later
有些加密中算法E使用一个密钥
in the course, there are ciphers where the
encrypter uses one key and the decrypter
解密算法D使用不同的密钥，但在这里我们只关注对称密码
uses a different key. But here we're just
going to focus on symmetric cipher where
它们使用的是同一个密钥，接下来让你们看看一些历史上加密的例子
both sides use the same key. Okay, so let
me give you a few historic examples of
第一个例子，也是最简单的，被称作置换加密
ciphers. The first example, the simplest
one is called the substitution cipher. I
我确信你们在幼儿园就玩过置换加密
am sure all of you played the substitution
ciphers when you were in kindergarten.
根本来说，置换加密的密钥就是置换表
Basically a key for a substitution cipher
is a substitution table that basically
最基本的来说就是如何置换值字母，因此对于这个例子，A将被映射C
says how to map our letters. So here for
example the letter A would be mapped to C,
B将被映射W，C将被映射N，一直这样下去
the letter B would be mapped to W the
letter C would be mapped to N so on and so
然后一直到Z被映射为A，这就是一个单钥置换加密的例子
forth and then the letter Z would be
mapped, say, to A. So this is one example
为了练习我们之前介绍的概念
of a key for a substitution cipher. So just
to practice the notation we introduced
加密一部分信息使用这个密钥，假设就是
before, the encryption of a certain
message using this key, let's say the
信息BCZA，这个信息就是使用这个密钥加密
message is BCZA, the encryption of this
message using this key here would be, is
一次转换一个字母，B--W,C--N,Z--A,A--C
done by substituting one letter at a time.
So B becomes W, C becomes N, Z becomes A,
因此BCZA就是对WNAC的加密，这就是的密文
and A becomes C. So the encryption of BCZA
is WNAC, and this defines the ciphertext.
同理的我们可以用这个密钥解密密文
Similarly we can decrypt the ciphertext using the same key and of course
我们将得到它原始的信息
we'll get back the original message.
Okay. So, just for historical
因为历史原因，这个有关置换密码的例子被叫做凯撒密码
reasons, there is one example of something
that's related to the substitution cipher
事实上凯撒密码根本不是真正的密码
called the Caesar cipher. The Caesar
cipher, actually, is not really a cipher
原因就是它不存在密钥
at all. And the reason is that it doesn't
have a key. What a Caesar cipher is, is
凯撒密码根本上是一个固定的置换表
basically a substitution cipher where the
substitution is fixed. Namely, it's a
也就是说它相当于一个变换，就像A--D,B--E,C--F等等
shift by three. So A becomes D, B becomes
E, C becomes F and so on and so forth.
那它是什么呢，Y变成B，Z变成C，它是一个应用于所有明文信息的固定置换
What is it, Y becomes B and Z becomes C.
It's a fixed substitution that's applied
重申一下，这不是加密，因为它没有密钥
to all plaintext messages. So, again,
this is not a cipher, because there is no
或者说密钥是固定的，如果攻击者知道加密原理
key, the key is fixed. So if an attacker
knows how our encryption scheme works, he
他可以很轻松的破解信息，这个密钥不是随机的
can easily decrypt the message. The key is
not random, and therefore, decryption is
因此一旦知道工作原理破解是很容易的
very easy once you understand how the
scheme actually works. Okay, so now, let's
现在让我们回到置换加密，这种加密中密钥选择是随机的
go back to the substitution cipher, where
the keys really are chosen at random, the
置换表选择也是随机的，让我们看看如何打破这种置换密码
substitution tables are chosen at random.
And let's see how we break this
其实这很简单。第一个问题是，
substitution cipher. Turns out to be very
easy to break. The first question is, how
密钥空间有多大，这里有多少种不同的密钥，总共有26个英文字母
big is the key space? How many different
keys are there, assuming we have 26
因此我想你们会说密钥的数量是26的阶乘
letters? So, I hope all of you said that,
the number of keys is 26 factorial,
因为一个密钥，一个置换密钥，就是26的排列组合
because, a key, a substitution key, is
simply a table, a permutation of all 26
26的排列组合就是26!
letters. The number of permutations of 26
letters, is 26 factorial. If you calculate
26!大约是2^88
this out, twenty-sixth factorial is about
two to the 88th, which means that
这意味着描述置换加密的密钥需要花费88比特
describing a key in a substitution cipher
takes about 88 bits. So, each key is
每种密钥被88比特表示，这作为密码空间大小非常合适
represented by about 88 bits. Now, this is
a perfectly fine size for a keyspace. In
事实上我们将看到加密是非常安全.或许，你知道，
fact, we're gonna be seeing ciphers that
are perfectly secure, or, you know, that
大致有这个大小的密码空间是足够安全的，然而，即使
are adequately secure, with key spaces
that are roughly of this size. However,
置换密码的空间是2^88，它仍然
even though the substitution cipher has a
large key space of size 2^88, it's
非常不安全，让我们看看如何破解它。破解它，我们
still terribly insecure. So let's see how
to break it. And to break it, we're going
将使用分析字母使用频率的方法，那么第一个问题是
to be using letter frequencies. So the
first question is, what is the most
英文中最常用的字母是什么呢，我猜你们都知道
frequent letter in English text? So I
imagine all of you know that, in fact, E
E就是最常用的字母，如果我们进行定量研究
is the most common letter. And that is
gonna, if we make it quantitative, that's
这将帮助我们破解置换加密，从而仅已知密文
gonna help us break a substitution cipher.
So just given the ciphertext, we can
我们就可以得到明文，我们的方法是，首先
already recover the plaintext. So the way
we do that is, first of all, using
利用英文字母的使用频率，看这个怎么操作。
frequencies of English letters. So here's
how this works. So you give me an
那么你给我一个使用置换加密的密文，我知道的只有
encrypted message using the substitution
cipher. All I know is that the plaintext
原文使用的是英文，我还知道E是最常用的字母
is in English and I know that the letter E
is the most frequent letter in English.
事实上，在标准英语文章中它出现的概率是12.7%
And in fact, it appears 12.7 percent of
the time in standard English texts. So
所以我要做的就是观察你给我的密文，我将
what I'll do is I'll look at the ciphertext you gave me and I'm going to count
统计出每个字母出现的次数，那么
how many times every letter appears. Now
the most common letter in the ciphertext
密文中出现最频繁的字母用很大可能就是字母E
is going to be the encryption of the
letter E with very high probability. So
现在我们得到求解密钥表一个入口，基本上
now I'm able to recover one entry in the
key table. Mainly the letter, mainly now I
在这些字母中我已经知道了E所对应的，第二常用的字母是T
know what the letter E maps to. The
next, most common letter in English is the
它占9.1%的概率，重复上面过程
letter T, that appears about 9.1 percent
of the time. So now again, I count how
计算密文中每个字母出现次数
many times each letter appears in the
ciphertext. And the second most frequent
第二常用的很有可能是T
letter is very likely to be the encryption
of the letter T. So now I've recovered a
这样我们就找到了第二个入口，然后继续这种方法
second entry in the key table. And I can
continue this way. In fact, the letter A
接下来是字母A，出现概率8.1%
is the next most common letter; it appears
8.1 percent of the time. So now I can
我们就可以肯定密文中第三常用对应的是A
guess that the third most common letter in
the ciphertext is the encryption of the
我们已经得到了密钥表中的三个入口
letter A. And now I've recovered three
entries in the key table. Well, so now
现在我们要做什么呢，余下的字母在英语中出现次数很相近
what do I do? The remaining letters in
English appear roughly same amount of
其他的几乎不出现像Q和X，我们好像困在这一步了
time, other than some rare letters like Q
and X. But we're kinda stuck at this
我们找到了密钥表中的三个入口，接下来怎么办呢
point. We figured out three entries in
the key table but what do we do next? So,
接下来我们使用成对字母的频率，我们也称它们
the next idea is to use frequencies of
pairs of letters. Sometimes these are
二连字，接下来我们需要数出密文中连字出现的次数
called digrams. So, what I'll do is, I'll
count how many times each pair of letters
当然我知道这是英文写的，最常用的成对字母
appears in the cipher text, and, I know
that in English, the most common pairs of
有he，an，in，th也是非常常用的字母对
letters are things like, HE, AN. IN, I
guess TH is another common pair of
这样我们知道密文中最频繁的连字
letters. And so I know that the most
common pair of letters in the ciphertext
就是这四对中的一个，通过试验，
is likely to be the encryption of one of
these four pairs. And so by trial and
我们可以找到找到密钥表的更多入口..元素，按照这种方法重复
error I can sort of figure out more entry ...
more elements in the key table and again
试验探错，我就可以得到整个的密钥表
by more trial and error this way by
looking at trigrams. I can actually figure
因此，事实上在置换加密还是易受攻击的
out the entire key table. So the bottom
line here is that in fact the substitution
而这是最差的可能的攻击，就是唯密文攻击
cipher is vulnerable to the worst possible
type of attack namely a ciphertext only
只要已知密文，就能破解出解密密钥
attack. Just given the ciphertext the
attack that can recover the decryption key
从而恢复出明文，因此，加密时使用置换加密
and therefore recover the original plaintext. So there's really no point in
是没有意义的，因为攻击者可以轻松
encrypting anything using the substitution
cipher, because the attacker can easily
地破译，这样如同清楚地发送明文效果一样。
decrypt it all; you might as well send
your plaintext completely in the clear.
接下来我们将快进到文艺复兴时期
So, now we're gonna fast-forward to the
Renaissance, and, I guess we're moving
也就是说，我们从罗马时代跳到了文艺复兴这期，
from the Roman Era to the Renaissance, and
look at a cipher designed by a fellow
来看一个叫Vigener(维吉尼亚)的哥们设计的密码，他生活在16世纪
named Vigener, who lived in the
sixteenth century. He designed a couple
他设计了一系列密码，现在我将展示其中一种的变体
of ciphers. Here I'm gonna show you a
variant of one of his ciphers, this is
它也被称作Vigener加密，在Vigener密码中，密钥是一个单词
called a Vigener cipher. So, in a
Vigener cipher, the key is a
这种情况下这个单词是CRYPTO，它由六个字母构成
word. In this case the word, is CRYPTO,
it's got six letters in it. And then to
然后为了加密信息，你要做的就是根据密钥重写信息
encrypt a message, what you do is, you
write the message under the key. So in
如果消息是“WHAT A NICE DAY TODAY”，然后按照需要重复地用密钥
this case the message is "WHAT A NICE DAY
TODAY" and then you replicate the key as
掩盖信息这种加密就是
many times as needed to cover the message.
And then the way you encrypt is basically,
将密钥字母加原文字母然后模26。这里给个例子说明一下
you add the key letters to the message
letters, modulo 26. So just to give
比如，Y加到A就得到Z
you an example here, for example, if you
add Y and A, you get Z. If you add T and
T加A得到U
A, you get U. And you do this for all the
letters. And remember, whenever you add,
对所有的字母都这样
you add modulo 26. So if you go past Z,
you go back to A. So, that's the
记住加的时候一定要模26，这样超过Z就会回到A
Vigener cipher. And in fact,
decryption is just as easy as encryption.
这就是Vigener加密，事实上解密和加密一样简单
Basically, the way you would decrypt is,
again, you would write the ciphertext
解密的方法就是在密钥下写出密文
under the key. You would replicate the key
and then you would subtract the key from
重复使用密钥，密文减去密钥就可以得到原文
the ciphertext to get the original plain
text message. So, breaking the Vigener
因此破译Vigener加密是相当容易的。让我们看看怎么做
cipher is actually quite easy. Let me
show you how you do it. The first thing we
首先我们假设知道密钥的长度
need to do is we need to assume that we
know the length of the key. So let's just
假设这种情况下密钥长度是六个
assume we know that. In this case, the
length of the key is six. And then what we
接下来我们就把明文6个6个分组，我们
do is we break the cipher text into groups
of six letters each, okay? So we're gonna
我们得到一串串这样的组。每一组都由六个字母组成
get a bunch, a bunch of groups like this.
Each one, contains six letters. And then
然后看一看每一组的第一个字母
we're gonna look at, the first letter in
each group. Okay? So, in this case, yes,
是的，我们正在看第一个字母，每六个字符
we're looking at the first letter, every
six characters. Now, what do we know about
关于这六个（应该是3个）字母我们知道什么呢
these six letters? We know that, in fact,
they're all encrypted using the same
事实上，他们加密使用的是一样的字母
letter in the ciphertext. All of these
are encrypted using the letter c. In other
都使用字母C加密, Z L W就是三个明文字母的转换
words. Z L W is a shift by three of the
plaintext letters. So if we collect all
如果我们收集了所有的字母，最常用的很可能是E的加密
these letters then the most common letter
among the set is likely to be the
E是最常用的英文字母
encryption of E, right? E is the most
common letter in English, therefore, if I
因此如果我们每寻找六个字母
look at every sixth letter, the most
common letter in that set is likely to be
最常用的的就是字母E的加密，那么我们假设事实上
the encryption of the letter E. Ahah! So
let's just suppose that in fact the most
最频繁的字母恰好还是H
common letter every sixth letter happens
to be the letter H. Then we know that E
就推出E加密钥的第一个字母得到H
plus the first letter of the key is equal
to H. That says that the first letter of
也就是说密钥第一个字母等于H减E，就是C
the key is equal to H minus E. And in fact
that is the letter C. So now we've
这样我们得出了密钥的第一个字母，对第二个字母重复以上过程
recovered the first letter of the key. Now
we can continue doing this with the second
那么，我们看一下每六个字符中的第二个字母
letter. So we look at the second letter in
every group of six characters and again,
重复试验，找到密文中最常用的的和我们已知最常用的
we repeat the same exercise. We find
the most common letter among the sets and
这个常用字母就是E的加密
we know that the most, this most common
letter is likely the encryption of E and
不管这个字母是什么
therefore whatever this letter, whatever
this most common letter is if we
减去E就可以得到密钥中的第二个字母
subtract 'E' from it we're going to get the
second letter of the key. And so on and so
重复这个过程，我们就可以得到密码中的第三个字母
forth. With, the third letter every six
characters. And this way we recover, the
这样依次就可以得到整个字母表，就可以破译信息了
entire key. And that allows us to
decrypt, the message. Now, the only caveat
唯一需要说明的是我们必须提前知道密钥的长度
is that I had to assume ahead of time that
I know the length of the key, which in
上面我们假设是6
this case is six. But if I don't know the
length of the key ahead of time, that's
但如果我们不知道长度，那也不是问题
not a problem either. What I would do is I
would run this decryption procedure,
我们要做的就是运行破译步骤，假设是1，再假设是2
assuming the key length is one. Then I'd
run it assuming the key length is two.
再假设长度是3，依次下去
Then I would run it assuming the key
lengths is three. And so on, and so on,
直到我们最后能得到信息，我们就得到有意义的破解
and so on, until finally I get a message.
I get a decryption that makes sense,
那的确有意义，一旦我们知道密钥的正确长度
that's sensical. And once I do that I know
that I've kind of recovered the right
我们就可以得到正确的密钥
length of the key and I know that
I've also recovered the right key and
然后就得到正确的信息，懂了吗
therefore the right message. Okay? So
very, very quickly, you can recover, you
非常快，你就可以破解Vigener加密，这唯密文攻击
can decrypt Vigener cyphers. Again,
this is a ciphertext only attack. The
有趣的是Vigener想到了很好的主意，模26
interesting thing is, Vigener had a
good idea here. This addition mod
的确是个好主意，以后我们会看到，就是在这里它被执行得非常
26 is actually a good idea, and we'll see
that later, except it's executed very
糟糕，这是我们将改正的一点，稍晚一点
poorly here. And so we'll correct that, a
little bit later. Okay, we're gonna
好吧，我们将从文艺复兴时期快进到19世纪
fast-forward now from the Renaissance to, to the nineteenth century where
这个时代很多东西开始用电，因此人们想设计使用电驱动的密码
everything became electric. And so people
wanted to design ciphers that use electric
这些加密被称作转子机，因为他们使用转子
motors. In particular, these ciphers are
called rotor machines because they use
一个较早的例子就是使用一个转子的Hibber机
rotors. So an early example is called the
Hibber machine which uses a single motor.
这里给你们一幅图片，这就是转子，我猜它在
Here you have a picture of this machine.
The, the motor, the, I guess the rotor is
这儿，密钥被这里的磁盘捕获，它被嵌入到磁盘的里面
over here. And the secret key is captured
by this disc here, it's embedded inside of
你每在键盘输入一个密钥它就旋转一个刻痕
this disc, which rotates by one notch
every time you press a key on the
所以你每敲一个键，盘转过一格
typewriter, okay? So every time you, that
you hit a key, the disc rotates by one
那这个密钥怎么工作呢，密钥实际上编码一个置换表
notch. Now what does this key do? Well,
the key actually encodes a substitution
因此，这个磁盘就是密钥
table. So ... and therefore, the disc actually
is the secret key. And as I said, this
正如我所说的，磁盘编码置换表，在这种情况下
disc encodes a substitution table. In this
case, if you happen to press C as the
如果你恰好第一字母按C，输出将会是字母T
first letter, output would be the letter
T. And then the disc would rotate by one
然后磁盘旋转一格，新的置换表就显示在这里
notch. After rotating, rotating by one
notch, the new substitution table becomes
你看到E移到上面去了
the one shown here. You see that E,
basically, moves up, and then the
余下的接在下面。想象一下这其实是一个由一格控制的二维
remaining letters move down. So imagine
this is basically a two dimensional
旋转磁盘。然后按下另一个字母。
rendering of the disc rotating by one
notch. Then you press the next letter. And
磁盘再次旋转 ，注意到N上移其它字母顺序接下
the disc rotates again. You notice again N
moved up and the remaining letters moved
特别的，如果我们敲击3次C，第一次
down. So in particular, if we hit the
letter C three times, the first time we
将会输出T，第二次输出S
would output, the output would be T, the
second time the output would be S, and the
第三次将会是K，这就是简单的转子机的工作方式
third time the output wold be K. So this
is how the single rotor machine works and
在它公布后很快就被使用字母频率
as it turned out very quickly after it was
advertised it was again broken basically
和连字频率和三连字频率的方法破解了
using letter frequency, digram
frequencies and trigram frequencies. It's
破译密钥，进而破译原文不是很难去
not that hard given enough ciphertext to
directly recover the secret key and then
再次说明这只是唯密文攻击
the message. Again, a ciphertext only
attack. So to kind of work against these
因此为了抵抗频率攻击，这种统计攻击
frequency attacks, these statistical
attacks, these rotor machines became more
这些转子机变得而越来越复杂，最终，你们肯定听过Enigma
and more complicated over time. Until
finally, I'm sure you've all heard of the
这是一种复杂的转子机
Enigma. The Enigma is a kind of
complicated rotor machine. It uses
它使用3到5个转子，还有不同版本的Enigma机
three, four, or five rotors. There are
different versions of the Enigma
给你们看一下3个转子的Enigma机，
machine. Here you see an example of the
Enigma machine with three rotors. The
Enigma机的密码是内置在转子里的。
secret key in the Enigma machine is the
initial setting of the rotors. Okay. So in
这种情况下，3个转子，会有26^3种可能的不同密钥
the case of three rotors there would be 26
cubed possible different keys. When you
当你从键盘输入时，转子就会以不同的速率旋转
type on the typewriter basically these
rotors here rotate at different rates.  Oh,
忘了说了这是4个转子的Enigma机图片
forgot to say this is a diagram of an Enigma
machine using four rotors. As you type on
当你在打字机上打字时，输出合适的密文字母
the typewriter the rotors rotate and
output the appropriate, letters of, the
这样密钥的数量就是26^4
ciphertext. So in this case the number
of keys is 26 to the fourth, which is two
这大约2^18,这是一个相当小的密钥空间
to the eighteen, which is relatively a
small key space. Today you can kind of,
今天你可以简单粗暴使用电脑检索2^88个不同的密钥
brute-force a search using a computer
through two to the eighteen different
这非常快，我们的智能手表能几秒内算出来
keys, very, very quickly. You know, my
wristwatch can do it in just a few
我想这个Enigma机使用相当少的空间
seconds, I guess. And so, these, this
Enigma machine was, already was using
我确信你们听过一个英国的破译者
relatively small key spaces. But I'm sure
you've all heard that the British
他在布莱奇利公园仅仅攻击了Enigma机就匹配了密文
cryptographers at Bletchley Park were
able to mount ciphertext only attacks on
他们在二战时破译了德军的密码
the Enigma machine. They were able to
decrypt German ciphers back in World, in
他们在世界大战的不同战役都扮演了重要角色
World War Two. And that played an
important role in many different battles
战争之后，那是机械时代的结束
during the war. After the war, I guess
that was the end kind of the mechanical
开启了数字时代，人们开始使用电脑
age and started the digital age where
folks were using computers. And as the
随着世界都开始使用电脑，政府意识到他们在从工业界购买
world kind of migrated to using computers,
the government realized that it's buying a
大量电子设备，因此政府希望从工业界购买设备时，希望
lot of digital equipment from industry.
And so they wanted industry to use a good
预装有好的加密机制
cipher so that when it buys equipment from
the, from industry, it would be getting
因此政府发出了数据加密标准的征集
equipment with, with a decent cipher. And
so the government put out this request for
一个联邦的数据加密标准
proposal for a data encryption standard,
a Federal data encryption standard. And
在这个课上，我们将详细谈论这个的影响
we're gonna talk about this effort, in
more detail later on in the course, but in
1974年，IBM的一个团队提出了一个密码，是DES，数据加密
1974 a group at IBM put together a cipher
that became known as DES, data encryption
标准，它成为了联邦的数据加密标准。DES的密钥空间
standard, which became a Federal standard
for encrypting data. The key space for DES
是2^56，如今来说相当小，但在1974年
is two to the 56, which is relatively
small these days, but was large enough
它足够大了，关于DES，另一个有趣的是，
back in 1974. And another interesting
thing about DES is, rather than, unlike
它不像转子机一次只能加密一个字节，
rotor machines which encrypt one character
at a time the data encryption standard
它能一次加密64比特，也就是8个字节，在后面的
encrypts 64 bits at a time, namely eight
characters at a time. And we'll see the
课程我们将明白其中的意义。因为DES使用
significance of this later on in the
course. Because DES uses such
如此小的密钥空间，如今可以使用暴力检索来破译
a small key space, these days it can be
broken by a brute-force search and so
所有如今DES被认为是不安全的，不允许在项目中使用
these days DES is considered
insecure and should not be used in
不幸的是，他仍然被使用在一些遗留系统中
projects. Unfortunately, it is used in
some legacy systems, but it definitely is
但现在很明显，它在没落，不会再用到新的项目上。
on its way out and definitely should not
be used in new projects. Today there are
如今已经有了新的加密方法，比如使用128比特密钥的AES。
new ciphers, things like the advanced
encryption standard which uses 128 bit
后面我们将会详细地讨论高级加密标准
keys. Again, we'll talk about the advanced
encryption standards in much more detail
这里有很多种其他的加密类型。这里我提一下
later on in the course. There are many,
many other types of ciphers. I mentioned
salsa20。我们马上就会看到为什么。这就是历史方面简短
Salsa20 here. We'll see why in just a
minute. But this is all for the quick
的介绍，现在我们就要开始学习技术资料了
historical survey and now we can get into
the more technical material.